is good to be with you once again today
we have a very special message and we're
going to be talking about what did not
happen at the cross what did not happen
at the cross let's go ahead and pause
for a word of Prayer
and then we're gonna jump right into the
message for today let's pray Heavenly
Father we want to ask in a special way
Lord that you would please speak to us
Lord that you would open our eyes open
our hearts give us understanding give us
wisdom Lord I pray that you would speak
through me today and I pray that this
message will impact us in a way that is
unexpected and that our hearts will be
set on fire for you in Jesus name we
pray amen and amen
I want to I want to start today by
sharing sharing with you a simple verse
I'm not going to go into the verse at
this moment but I will be referring back
to this verse as we go through this
presentation it is found in proverbs 26
verse 20 and I'm only going to quote a
part of the verse it's a part that I
want to focus on very simply it says
where there is no wood the fire goes out
we're all familiar with the parable of
the ten virgins yes Matthew chapter 25
describes their a story of ten virgins
five or wise and five are what five are
foolish and the five wise virgins in
fact all ten virgins have oil but five
of them the foolish ones do not bring
enough oil and as a result of them not
bringing enough oil what eventually
happens the fire goes out the fire goes
out what would you say is the similarity
between where there is no wood the fire
goes out and having no oil the fire goes
out what is the what is the purpose of
both the wood and the oil in those in
those verses say again okay it's fuel
it's fuel
it keeps the fire burning how many of
you aware of what fire represents in the
Bible
all right the fire one of the reference
representations of fire is that fire is
symbolic of the Holy Spirit but fire is
also symbolic of God's love amen so Song
of Solomon chapter 8 verses 6 through 8
the Bible there describes love or uses
fire as a symbol of love and love is
really the basis of the entire gospel
amen love is what leads to forgiveness
love is what leads to the desire to go
and share the good news
love is the basis of everything and so
when we find that we have a church that
struggles into the
Department of forgiveness that struggles
in the department of loving one another
we can come to a conclusion that when
those struggles happen it is because
there is not enough fire are you with me
there is not enough fire in other words
there is a problem in our church and
it's a fire problem
it's a fire problem by the way this is
why the Bible describes God's people as
being luke warm they have we have a fire
problem and so what we need to
understand all of it and what we need to
what what we need to get what we need to
understand is this where there is no
wood the fire goes out where there is no
wood the fire goes out I'm gonna say
that one more time
where there is no wood the fire goes out
I'm gonna say it one more time where
there is no wood the fire goes out now
you see me doing this and I suppose that
in perhaps all of your minds you now get
what I'm saying the basis of our fire is
what happened at Calvary the basis of
love the basis of forgiveness the basis
of everything that pertains to the
Christian life to the Christian walk the
fuel for our Christian experience is at
the cross
and and as a result of this we should
have our minds totally stayed upon what
happened at the cross in other words we
should continually be looking looking up
because it is in looking up Jesus at a
9-5 you want
lift up from the earth will do what draw
all men unto me it is by looking to the
cross that we come to the place that we
will have enough fuel to forgive we will
have enough fuel to love we will have
enough fuel to evangelize to witness we
will have enough fuel to overcome and so
again the reason why we struggle with
these things is I would say very simply
we don't have enough fuel we don't have
enough fire how do you get that fire as
I just said it's sent looking to Jesus
it's about looking at what he did for us
on the cross the Bible says we love him
ok let's let's let's switch it up a
little bit I'm gonna put another word in
there if love is symbolized in the Bible
by fire then we fire him because he
first fired us right that's how we get
fire by studying the depth of love
revealed in the Son of God for us that
is what sets us on fire now you've heard
the term fighting fire with fire do you
remember when the truth of Israel were
in the wilderness and the Bible says
that they were going through the
wilderness and they began to murmur
against God and then fiery serpents
remember that fiery serpents started
coming up out of the wilderness and by
out of the sand and biting them fiery
serpents and so what does God told Moses
to do make another fiery Serpent and put
it upon a pole and wait and when a
person was bitten by the fiery serpents
on the ground once they looked at the
fiery serpent on the pole which was a
symbol of
Jesus Jesus's fire neutralized the fire
did you catch that just not the fire of
Jesus neutralizes the venom of the enemy
look up look up don't look at your
wounds look up how many of us like
looking at our wounds when we get them
it's almost natural you get a wound you
look at the wound and you try to do
everything you can to fix the wound but
Jesus told them and though in the
wilderness look up to me don't focus on
the wound look at me look at me
I want you to come with me to Revelation
chapter 6 because we need to see
something that absolutely is absolutely
mind-blowing and I'm praying today that
I will be able to get this across to you
in the way that it needs to be presented
because this is heavy
you see I believe that once we discover
what really happened at the cross and
what actually didn't let me say this
once we discover what did not happen at
the cross by the way that is the title
of this message what did not happen it
sounds like a strange silent because so
often we focus on what what happened at
the cross but today we're going to be
talking about what did not happen at the
cross and let me tell you what did not
happen at the cross is so mind-blowing
that I hope it changes your life forever
come with me to Revelation chapter 6
Revelation chapter 6 we're gonna begin
reading from verse 12 when you get there
please say Amen the Bible says and I
beheld when he had opened the sixth seal
and lo there was a great earthquake and
the Sun became black as sackcloth of
hair and the moon became as blood and
the stars of heaven fell
to the earth even as a fig tree casteth
casteth her untimely figs when she is
shaken of a mighty wind and the heaven
departed as a scroll when it is rolled
together and every mountain and Island
were moved out of their place and the
kings of the earth and the great men and
the rich men and the chief captains and
the mighty men and every bondman and
every free man what did they do they hid
themselves in the dens and in the rocks
of the mountains and said to the
mountains and rocks fall on us and hide
us from the face of him that sitteth on
the throne and from the wat the wrath of
the lamb for the great day of his wrath
is come and who shall be able to stand
now someone tell me what is this what
are these verses talking about what are
they pointing to what event they're
pointing to the second coming
they are pointing to the destruction of
the world now now we are already in the
midst of a sixth seal and I'm not going
to get into too much detail about this
but in a very literal sense this is
these are the events that will take
place when Jesus comes again there's
going to be an earthquake there's going
to people going to be running for their
lives it's not it's called the day of
the wrath of God the day of the Lord
have a question for you how many of you
have ever had a an experience where you
nearly died where you nearly died I'm
not talking about necessarily a
near-death experience like you know you
were but like something happened where
you may have stepped out into the road
and sin and you weren't looking and you
could have been hit by a car or you know
you were you could have been in the
wrong place at the wrong time and you
know that things would not have ended
well and you think how much different
things would be if that happened to you
for one you wouldn't be here right now
obviously right and so many things would
change based upon that come back with me
to the book of Matthew chapter 27
Matthew chapter 27
and in Matthew 27 we're not going to
read a much of Matthew 27 at this point
but in Matthew 27 who can tell me what's
going on here towards the this is what
right this is right before the cross and
in fact it takes us into the cross and
it describes the the the last moments of
Jesus's life where he is on the cross
he's crying out my God my God why is
that forsaken me this is the end of
jesus's life now
once again when we study the events of
the cross we are looking at the things
that happened but we don't typically
think of the things that did not happen
and let me say when I first saw this I
know I'm building you up when I first
saw this I was just like whoa I was just
like oh like this is absolutely like
just do this right now
you're here right now amen praise now
you have no idea what I just told you to
do that but you will shortly soon hang
on something happens we're going to go
back to the book of Revelation so come
back there with me back to the book of
Revelation and something happens in
John's experience that sets the
foundation for what we will be looking
at it's found in Revelation chapter 4
and Revelation chapter 5 now in
Revelation chapter 4 by the way the book
of Revelation was written sometime
around 95 or 96 ad who can tell me when
did Jesus die
alright 31 of these so 31 a days so this
is like you know 50 60 years later that
that John is having this revelation of
Jesus Christ okay so about when John is
having this revelation Jesus has been in
heaven for years it would be so far just
say nn-now revelation revelation chapter
4 john sees verse 4 verse 1 after
I looked and behold a door was opened in
heaven and the first voice which I heard
was as it were the voice of a trumpet
talking with me which said come up
hither and I was so these things which
must be Hereafter
and immediately I was in the spirit and
behold there was said in heaven there
was a throne set in heaven and one sat
on the throne and so if you read the
book of Revelation you'll remember if
you're familiar with this chapter John
sees the heavenly father seated on the
throne and then if we go over to chapter
5 the Bible says and I saw in the right
hand of him that sat on the throne a
book written within and on the backside
sealed with seven seals and I saw strong
angel proclaiming with a loud voice who
is worthy to open the book and to loose
the seals thereof and no man in heaven
nor in earth nor under the earth was
able to open the book neither to look
thereon and I wept much because no man
was found worthy to open and to read the
book neither to look thereon now pause
for a second how is that even possible
how is it possible that no man was found
worthy to open the book can any of you
come to any conclusions based off of
this text when what is what time span is
John in when he looks and he sees that
there is nobody alive anywhere that is
able to open the book where's Jesus
think about this where is Jesus if Jesus
is alive surely he's worthy to open the
book amen but when John looks he says
there was no one able to open the book
is this true in 95 ad no it's not
was it true at any point in 31 ad when
in 31 ad when Jesus is what is when
Jesus is dead
in other words in John's mind he has
been transported back in time to where
Jesus is in the grave but is not and is
not alive that's why no one has found
worthy to do what open the book and the
Bible says that John begins to weep
profusely
why is he weeping what book is this yet
this book has how many seals on it seven
seals and we know that right after in
Revelation chapter 6 we begin to see
what the seven seals are very
interesting you know what's one of the
things contained in the seals let me
show you
Revelation chapter 6 verse 9 Revelation
chapter 6 verse 9 the Bible says here
and when he had opened the fifth seal I
saw under the altar the souls of them
that were slain for the word of God and
for the testimony which they had held
and they cried with a loud voice how
long O Lord holy and true dost thou not
judge and avenge our blood on them that
dwell on the earth so who are these
people that are found under the fifth
seal those that have been slain for
Christ from the beginning of time
all the way up until that point so in
other words in this book are the names
of the righteous dead are you with me so
far are you with me in this book are the
names of the righteous dead when we get
to Revelation chapter 7 we find
mentioned the 144,000 and also this
number called the great multitude which
are the names of the righteous living in
other words beloved in this book are the
names of the redeemed are you with me so
why is John weeping
if the book is never opened what happens
to the names of the redeemed they're not
redeemed in other words this book
contains the future of humanity the
future of planet Earth and when John
realizes there's no one found worthy to
open the book
he is also realizing that if the book is
not open then that is it for human
history you are not here I don't know if
you catch that guys if the book is not
opened you there is no socal
camp-meeting 2019 if the book is not
opened you are not sitting here you
don't have children you don't exist you
don't have parents if the book is not
open the future of Earth and humanity is
at stake but there's good news because
someone is found worthy to open the book
and that person is Jesus but but I need
you to see something here because in
order to understand in order to
understand what actually happened that
enabled Jesus to open the book I need
you to come back to the Old Testament
and we're going to take a look at the
book of Exodus chapter 32 now how many
of you know what happened in Exodus 32
Exodus 32 is the story of the golden
calf femur of that and what I'm about to
show you is the significance of John
weeping remember this book contains the
future of humanity and John is weeping
because in his mind there's no one
worthy to open the book
in Exodus 32 the Bible speaks of this
story where the children of Israel Moses
have gone up into the Wilden up into the
mountain the children of Israel think
that he is not going to return and they
build a golden was they build a golden
calf and after they build a golden calf
they begin to celebrate they begin to
dance around the calf and then of course
Moses comes back he discovers what they
have done and it's just not good not as
a question it was this building of a
golden calf and a fence to God yes it
was not offense to God and God calls
Moses back up the Mount Moses is going
to go back up to the Mount but let me
share with you what God said notice with
me Exodus 32 and verse 10 Exodus 32
verse 10 the Bible says here now
therefore God speaking of Moses in fact
let's go to verse 9 and Lord said to
Moses I've seen these people and behold
it is a stiff-necked people now
therefore let me alone that my wrath may
wax hot against them and that I may want
consume them and I will make of thee a
great nation is God upset here
absolutely because God is God has wrath
against sin are you with me and what did
they do they sin was it a pretty big sin
absolutely come with me to Deuteronomy
chapter 9 verse 13 and 14 Deuteronomy
chapter 9 Deuteronomy 9 verse 13 and 14
the Bible says here speaking of the same
incident furthermore the Lord spake unto
me saying I have seen these people and
the old it is a stiff-necked people let
me alone that I may destroy them and
blot out their name from under heaven
not what does that mean yeah that's
eternal destruction that's your name
being blotted out of the book of what
the book of life again were these wicked
acts these were wicked acts in which God
was saying listen the result of your
wicked act is that I will blot your name
out of the book of
life does God condone sin absolutely not
and we see that this event was enough
for God to say I'm about to wipe out all
these people think of Genesis chapter 6
remember the story of the flood the
Bible says the imaginations of men's
hearts were only evil continually and as
a result of that sin of their sins
against God
what does God do he sends a flood that
basically wipes out the entire world but
good news
you know Earth continues on God found
Noah and raised up a new people are you
with me in Genesis chapter 18 you have a
story of sodom and gomorrah and because
of whatever sins they were committing it
was enough for God to say I'm coming
down and I'm wiping out this whole city
were those pretty big things now I want
you to I'm gonna give you a question
here and I want you to tell me what you
think the golden calf on a scale of 1 to
10 where would you put those things 11
okay let's let's go with 11 on a scale
of 1 to 10 we're gonna go with 11 the
flood the things that people were doing
in that time their sins scale of 1 to 10
allowing 11 word you place it 10 Sodom
and Gomorrah where would you place that
are all sins are 10 okay well you know
stealing candy may not be a 10 I
wouldn't put that out of 10 I'd say it's
still sin yes but there are degrees of
sin right and no sin is excusable I'm
just saying that even in the destruction
of the wicked some will be punished
longer than others because of the degree
of sin let me ask you a question though
how many parents do we have in here okay
so let's say parents you know I walk up
to you or someone walks up to you and
they're like I don't like you what do
you do come on good Christian what do
you do what do you do you what do you do
you thank him you pray for him you'll be
offended yes but what do you do come on
good Christian what do you do you pray
for him
you forgive ya you turn the other cheek
wow we are really having problems here
today you try you know you try to do the
right thing as Christians we're supposed
to let that stuff roll off of our back
now
same person comes up to your child and
says in your presence to your child I
don't like you how many of you keep your
cool that's blood beloved on a scale of
one to ten what do you think about the
sin of putting the Son of God to death
there is no scale now remember this God
was willing to blob out an entire nation
for making a golden calf I don't know if
you are feeling me he was willing to
blot out an entire nation because of a
golden calf he destroyed that a city
because of whatever sins they were doing
was grieving them in Grievous enough to
God but do you think there is a
difference now when it comes to actually
putting the Son of God to death
Moses is on top of the Mount and he's
pleading with God and Moses comes up
with us with this idea you remember what
did Moses say he goes to God he says
listen don't block them out block me out
you remember that
in other words Moses is in this
situation where he's like okay God is
angry with them because he is they have
sinned and God is a just God amen but I
love those hard-headed people so much
God I have an idea I don't know if this
is word about God listen how about you
brought me out so that they may live now
our God and Moses friends are you think
they're pretty good friends yeah they're
pretty good friends and yet God says to
Moses you remember he says you know he
that sins against me his name shall
habla Moses you can't stand in a place
for someone else but nonetheless because
of Moses is intercession God allows the
children of Israel another chance amen
but beloved I need you to understand
something Moses was not Jesus and now
God sends his son you know the Bible
says in Isaiah 53 verse 5 the
chastisement of our peace was upon him
that Jesus took a penalty for us you
know that in Isaiah 63 I want you to
turn there with me Isaiah chapter 63
Isaiah 63 beginning with verse 3 Isaiah
chapter 63 I don't know if anyone is
back there that can help me but my iPad
is low on battery power so if I can
maybe have someone come and give me some
power here power for my iPad that would
be great
Isaiah 63 I don't know if that's going
to reach but uh there's a plug right
there in the front Isaiah 63 verses 3 &
4 when you're there please say Amen
as they is 63 verses 3 & 4 the Bible
says I have trodden the winepress alone
and of the people there was none with me
for I will tread them in mine anger and
trample them in my fury and their blood
shall be sprinkled upon my garments and
I will stain all my raiment for the day
of vengeance is mine and the year of my
rid of my redeemed is come you remember
this verse is familiar thank you this
verse this verse there we go
okay I'm good now thank you thank you
thank you all thank you thank you okay
this verse I have tread the winepress of
the wrath of God alone it's pointing to
what Jesus did on the cross on our
behalf amen and he's talking about this
as as as the day of God's wrath I want
you to catch that guys he's speaking
about this as the day of God's wrath in
other places it is called the day of the
Lord not us really strange guys the day
of the Lord is the day that he tread the
winepress of the wrath of God alone how
how does that work remember in Matthew
27 verse 45 come with me now if you
chapter 27 and verse 45 and now you're
about to see something unfold beloved
that if you're thinking ahead of me your
your mind is about to be blown I need
you to see this Matthew 25 verse 40 44
the thieves also which were crucified
with him cast the same in his teeth and
verse 45 now from the sixth hour
there was once darkness over all the
land unto the ninth hour pause for a
second Jesus is on the cross the father
is looking down at what the world is
doing to his son I want you to tell me
what emotions do you think are going
through the father's heart what do you
think what is he what's occurring on
earth they're what they're killing his
son how does God feel about sin
what is his what is his emotion toward
sin wrath rap so imagine with me God is
looking down on earth and and remember
now he was about to wipe out a whole
nation because they made a golden calf
now we just said the golden calf on a
scale of 1 to 10
someone said 11 and you actually thought
it was something big like Oh 11 that's
an inanimate object a thing now here
they are putting to death the son of God
and let me ask you what do you think God
is thinking as he's looking down at this
how does God react to sin with justice
you you planet earth you are putting my
son to death seriously you're putting my
son to that seriously now let me ask you
how many fathers again once again the
fathers what emotion is going through
your heart
as you watch someone out there beating
up on your son and you just happen to
turn around and you catch them beating
up on your son
what would I mean this is one of those
no you know no you didn't know you there
was darkness why do you think there was
darkness why do you think the Sun
stopped shining beloved listen to me
listen to me listen to me the Sun the
Sun stops shining because something was
about to begin
notice with me Psalm 18 Psalm the 18th
Psalm verse 3 Psalm 18 verse 3 the Bible
says here I will call upon the Lord who
is worthy to be praised so shall I be
saved from mine enemies the sorrows of
death compus me and the floods of
ungodly men made me afraid that's not
familiar to anyone
yeah whose words are these who else said
these words do these sound reflective of
what happened to Jesus on the cross
let's keep reading in my distress I
called upon the Lord and cried unto my
God my God my God my God my God hold on
hmm well verse we in verse 6 he heard my
voice out of his temple and my cry came
before him even into his ears then no no
no no stop don't read yet don't yet
don't stop look up at me look up at me
your sons crying out to you and you hear
his voice because ungodly men have
surrounded him and you hear his voice
daddy daddy and you turn around let me
what emotion have you turned around with
what are you about to do are you about
to throw down that's you know a term for
get busy are you about to get busy your
sons calling out for you and he's saying
how ungodly men are surrounded me what's
your demeanor what's your spin what's
your attitude you touch my son alright
it's over
verse 7 then the earth shook and
trembled pause for a second when Jesus
died was there an earthquake the earth
shook and trembled the foundations of
the hill also moved them were shaken
because he was walked rough
there was a stair went up a smoke out of
his nostrils and fire out of his mouth
devoured coals were kindled by it he
bowed the heavens also and came down and
darkness was under his feet he came down
he did what he came down on man's
question how many you have ever read the
description of Jesus on the cross in the
darkness into the book the book the dark
desire of Ages do you know where she
says that God came down in the darkness
right here Psalms 18 that's what's being
described God comes down but he's
cloaked in darkness so watch this there
is darkness there's an earthquake does
that sound familiar why does that sound
familiar that sounds like what happens
when that sounds like what's supposed to
happen at the second coming when God
destroys the entire planet y'all not
yeah no you're you're probably thinking
right now I hope that's what you're
doing your problem you see beloved in
the sixth seal the opening of the sixth
seal there is darkness there's an
earthquake and there's a destruction of
the entire planet in other words beloved
have you ever watched those movies you
know where they have the the bomb that
is set and there's a timer going down
and when that timer hits everything's
gonna go
but love it on the cross the wrath of
God against sinners check this out
is being balanced by his son forgive
them for they don't know what they are
doing wait y'all gotta catch this guy's
you have to catch this because that
darkness was the beginning of the end of
the earth go like this
just let your head you are here today
because the cross of Christ listen to me
literally saved your life see we only
think Oh the cross fish no no no you had
an opportunity to be born your future
was secured because of what Jesus did on
the cross now I need you to imagine this
guys because this is mind-blowing what
did not happen at the cross is that the
earth was not destroyed when it totally
deserved it
what you mean all this time rejecting
God and not caring about God I am here
even though I don't believe in God I am
here because of what Christ did for me
at the cross oh my goodness you know I
mean wait wait you mean you mean the
earthquake you mean the the the the
darkness
you mean all of that was God and yet
being restrict were see and just
this warring with each other Jesus is on
the cross pleading not only is he on the
cross pleading but while he's doing it
the very people who don't realize that
they are about to be blotted out are
mocking him spitting upon him making fun
of the Son of God not realize the
imminent danger did God have every right
to destroy planet Earth in 31 ad and
still be just and still be merciful
every right but there stands one person
the very person on whom the sins of the
world have been placed the very person
who is mocking who is being mocked by
the world and that one person is doing
what Moses did back there on the
mountain except this time he's doing it
on Mount Calvary do you remember when
Jesus cries out my God my God why hast
thou forsaken me you know what you know
in the morning the the the discussion is
go unknown I'm sorry in the evenings the
discussions going on about Jonah and you
know how Jonah and when you want you to
think about this the storm was upon the
ship the storm was about to destroy the
ship and Jonah says throw me overboard
and it will save the ship do you catch
this guys Jesus was thrown overboard if
you will Jesus went into the grave his
death stopped the destruction of our
earth when he cries out my God my God
why has stopped
check this out guys my god my god why is
out for sake of me did the father
forsake the son no where was he
right there where beside him in the what
in the darkness so Jesus could not sense
his father's presence why did the father
hide his presence because what because
if he had revealed himself we would all
be dead you guys I need you I need you
to think this through the father draws
close to his son but he cannot reveal to
his son that he is there because to do
so would be to destroy the earth the
very people that are mocking his son
talk about justice and mercy
so Christ cries out my God my God why
has not forsaken me and he's pleading to
his father do not forsake me how many of
you how many of you think he's doing why
is he doing this why is he crying out my
god my god don't forsake me because what
there's a separation between the minutes
father yes
he's feeling the wrath yes what else
because of all the sins he's carrying
right yeah yeah like all of our you know
all of our answers typical answers good
answers but God's I need you to catch
this here do you remember when Abraham
God came to Abraham said Abraham I'm
going to destroy Sodom and Gomorrah so
Abraham's like okay okay all right hold
on a second let me ask you if there are
50 people found will you spare him then
he begins to go down 45 right
30 35 20 comes down to 10 I believe it
is if there's ten righteous people there
will you spirit and God says I'll scary
I'm as a Christian what do you think
Jesus is doing on the cross father I
know that you I know your wrath against
sin and I know what you're about to do
to this planet but listen listen guys
Jesus knew that he could not pray if
there are 50 because he knew there
weren't 50 he knew there weren't 40
there weren't 20 there were not even 12
there wasn't five it wasn't for there
was only one and that one was him so he
is now standing as the representative of
the entire planet and the reason he's
saying don't forsake me is not because
hey dad you know we had as we know he's
saying don't forsake me because if you
do
I feel like just walking off right now
this is like by hey if you forsake me
the book with your name in it attending
Soquel can't meaning 2019 will not be
opened and if it is not opened then
humanity has no future what did not
happen at the cross is just as important
as what happened at the cross you see
beloved there's something else you need
to understand and that is this that
Jesus it was not guaranteed for Jesus to
succeed in his mission it was a risk
Jesus had the freedom of choice the free
he could have sinned that's why he took
on our flesh that he if he could not
have sin he could not have intended but
he took in our flesh in order that he
could be tented how many of you remember
the story of the man of God anyone ever
heard read that story about the man of
God that's what he's called he has no
name he's just called the man of God
they're not sound like a bag of tea what
does his people's called you oh there
goes the man of God in this story the
man of God is sent by God to one of
Israel's Kings and the man of God
prophesize against this king and you
remember the story you know the king
goes out to reach for the man of God and
then his hand dries up remember that and
when his hands rise up the man of God
heel
his withered hand the man of God man of
God is a righteous title guys it's a
time that someone who is so well known
someone who is so uh just youth you he
he just he is filled apparently with the
presence of God he's called the man of
God the man of God heals this man's
withered hand and then the Bible says
that he begins to go on his way why
because God tells him do not go back the
way you came
and if anyone invites you to eat do not
eat in that place remember that story
and so the King says after he heals his
hand the king says hey come eat with me
and he says no I will not eat God told
me not to eat and he goes on and then
there were two boys there who had a
father who the Bible says was also a
prophet and so he comes back and the two
sons go back to the Father they tell him
what happened and he says which way did
the man of God go and they tell him so
he goes after the man of God and he says
hey come eat with me my house and the
man of God says no I will not eat and
then the false prophet says hey wait a
minute I am a prophet also and God told
me you can come and eat and what does
the madam what does the man of God do he
goes and what ends up happening to him
he is killed by what a lion a devouring
lion seeking whom he may devour beloved
why is that story in the Bible listen to
me God is no respecter of persons
wait so you didn't catch this the man of
God sent by God heals a withered hand
and it's tempted three times y'all not
feeling me the first time over tempted
over appetite young beloved that story
is in the Bible to show us that God is
no respecter of persons and Jesus
himself who was the alternate man of God
had he gone against his father
there would have been no hope for
humanity you have to understand the risk
and I think what happens beloved where
there is no wood the fire goes out what
happens with so many of us is that we
don't really understand what took place
at the cross and what did not happen at
the cross and as a result of that our
fire is not really all that fiery he
loved us we love him because he first
loved us and where is his love
demonstrated its demonstrated at the
cross and if we don't understand what he
did for us at the cross no wonder we
don't have enough love to forgive
someone else oh yeah because what they
did is bigger in our minds than what
Christ did at the cross or what did not
happen at the cross you guess what I'm
saying what that person said to you is
way bigger than what Jesus did at the
cross that's why the devil doesn't want
us study in the cross that's why he
doesn't want us focusing on Christ
that's why he doesn't want us looking up
because he knows that fire he knows that
you fight fire with fire he doesn't want
you getting on fire he doesn't want the
fire of God's love ignited in your heart
because he knows if that happens that is
the fuel that fuels forgiveness that is
the fuel that fuels evangelism that is
the fuel that gets you walking the way
that God wanted you to walk in the first
place that's the feel that allows the
five wise virgins to make it into the
kingdom but other when we begin to
understand just how amazing just how
multi-dimensional the sacrifice of
Christ was for us on Calvary just as we
begin to see how
this was because beloved we study so
many other things and fail to see that
Jesus and his sacrifice is the center of
all scriptures you guys are familiar
with a man by the name of David you
remember the story where David has been
Bathsheba's husband killed because he
gets her pregnant and the Bible says
that the prophet Nathan comes to David
and exposes his sin and says you are
that man and then David in that moment
of realizing man what have I done what
was I thinking
David repents and we say praise God
because David repented but the prophet
Nathan goes on to say but the child that
you are going to have that but she was
pregnant with that child is going to die
and we think what in the world that's
not fair why does David get to live he's
the one that sin and we look at that
stir and say man I wonder about God's
character until we realize something you
see that child is not given a name in
the scriptures we don't know who the
child is all we know is that it's a male
child and if it's a male child that
makes this child the son of David
wait the son of David was brought into
this world because of sin and died that
someone else might live
you got talking about the son of it I'm
talking about back there in the book the
book of kings or chronicles whoever it
is the son of David
that boy was brought into the world
because of sin and died that someone
else might live and now we suddenly get
the picture the reason that story is in
the Bible is to show us that Jesus who
is the true son of David was brought
into this world because of our sins and
died that we might live but other that's
fire when you begin to see how much God
loved us that is fire that is that is
God showing us listen I'm firing you so
that you can fire me I'm loving you so
that you can love me you see God Jesus
cried out my God my God why has thou
forsaken me
why would he even think that God would
forsake him listen in the Old Testament
remember this no one with a blemish
could come before the Lord you rember
that here Jesus is with the whole sin of
the world upon him and the sacrifice is
pleading before his father except the
sacrifice but remember God hates what
sin can you imagine that the son covered
insane the father wanting to reach
and yet he has become sin remember guys
it was not a brazen lamb that Moses put
up on a pole it was not a brazen dove it
was a serpent Christ became sin for us
so beloved when John now sees in the
book of Revelation he hears his voice
wait come come with me
revelation chapter 5 Revelation chapter
5 I wanted to imagine this to me I just
want you to imagine the drama of this
okay like Jesus has 10 seconds left to
live the clock is ticking down and that
second one Jesus dies and all creation
not earth but all creation has frozen
what is about to happen to Planet Earth
they just killed the son of God is a
planet going to exist in a few seconds
from now
and that clock counts down to one and
the universe sees that the father has
accepted the sacrifice of his son this
earth is here right now literally
because of what Jesus did on the cross
John hears in Revelation chapter 5
Revelation chapter 5 revelation 5 on
believe it is verse 6 verse 5 and one of
the elders said unto me weep not behold
the Lion of the tribe of Judah the root
of David has prevailed to open the book
and to loose the seven seals thereof and
I beheld and lo in the midst of the
throne and of the four beasts and in the
midst of the elders stood a lamb what as
it had been slain having the seven horns
and seven eyes which are the seven
spirits of God sent forth into all the
earth and he came and took the book out
of the right hand of him that sat on the
throne and we had and when he had taken
the book the four beasts and the four
and twenty elders fell down before the
lamb having every one of them harps and
golden vials full of odours which are
the prayers of the saints and they sung
a new song saying thou art worthy to
take the book and to open the seals
thereof for thou was slain and has what
redeemed us to God by thy blood out of
every kindred and tongue and people and
nation Wow and then the seven seals are
opened the first seal is a rider on a
white horse representing the gospel
going forth into all the world with
great power
you are here because of that rider on
the white horse
do you chattel I just said you are here
because of that rider on the white horse
because of the gospel going forth but it
never would have happened had God made
it out to us what we deserved so you
should appreciate life a little bit
differently now you didn't know that you
almost didn't we're not here and when
you begin to realize whoa I almost was
not here like when you have that
experience where you almost die you tend
to live life differently and beloved I
believe that that is what needs to
happen with the Church of God we need to
understand that we are here by the grace
of God have you ever stopped to think
about that you know when we say oh yeah
you know like and God had a plan for me
probably none of the human race is here
by the grace of God because we all
should have been destroyed listen we
love him because he first one loved us
because of what he did on the cross for
us we should never doubt the love of God
to doubt the love of God is a sin that
is probably worse than what happened at
Calvary to doubt God's power to forgive
you to doubt God's willingness to
cleanse you to make you to doubt God how
can you in light of the cross
listen the story of Moses you remember
that God had come to Joseph and told
Joseph Joseph listen your people are
going to be enslaved for how long how
long four hundred years and at the end
of four hundred years something happened
God brought a man by the name of Moses
on the scene and as God brings Moses on
the scene we know that Moses is called
because he is about to deliver the
children of Israel from captivity to
where to the promised land Moses leads
the children of Israel out of captivity
to the promised land now remember this
Moses does not is not allowed to enter
into the promised land remember that but
he sees a promised land instead Joshua
is going to lead the children of Israel
into the Promised Land so so there's
this transition of power between from
Moses to Joshua and and and Joshua takes
over crosses the Jordan and he leads the
twelve tribes of Israel over the Jordan
I need you to follow this history
carefully when Joshua leads the children
of Israel over over the Jordan he goes
into conflict he goes in a battle and he
fights against what city Jericho and he
defeats it and then he fights against
another place called AI and remember
they go out they send a few planned you
know relatively few people they get beat
and Josh was like what happened and God
shows him that someone stole a garment
all these different things and then
Joshua goes out to fight against air
again and defeats ai after this the
Bible says that Joshua did something
that Moses had commanded them to do on
the other side of the Jordan so Joshua
takes the twelve tribes of Israel and he
places them on two mountains one is
called Mount Ebal and the other one is
called Mount Jerry's
and what happens is Joshua begins to
read are these these blessings and
cursings that God told them to read on
the other side of the Jordan and when
Joshua begins to read these blessings he
reads and I believe it's in Deuteronomy
chapter in fact let's go there
Deuteronomy chapter 11 I need you to see
this Deuteronomy chapter 11 Deuteronomy
11 and verse I'm sorry Deuteronomy 28
Deuteronomy 28 and and beginning with
verse 3 it says bless yourself I'll be
in the city blessed shalt thou be in the
field
blessed shall be the fruit of thy body
the fruit of thy ground the fruit of thy
cattle the increase of mankind and it
goes on it's feets 9 blessings in all
how many everyone 9 now if God blessed
you once how many of you would be happy
about that if God said to you I'm gonna
give you a blessing how many of you that
would be worth everything in life but he
blesses nine times
amen how many of you could use those 9
blessings so so first he reads the
blessings on Mount Gerizim and then he
reads the curses on Mount Ebal and
that's the scary part because if you're
in Deuteronomy chapter 28 or you will
notice that from verses 1 to 14 are all
the blessings but from verse 15 so I
believe it's verse 63 are all the curses
and these are priests if God cursed you
one time how many of you would be like
okay God that's enough but beloved in
this chapter there are something like 55
or 56 verses of curses if you don't obey
God this would be the mountain of curses
how many of you would respond in a good
way hearing these curses how many of you
would be afraid of God hearing these
curses
why is the story in the Bible listen
beloved it was 400 years that children
of Israel spent in captivity before
Moses comes on the scene do you realize
that it was 400 years between the last
book of the Old Testament and the first
book of the New Testament Moses comes on
the scene and his job was to deliver the
children of Israel to see the promised
land you know who came upon the scene in
the New Testament John the Baptist John
the Baptist had a mission it was to lead
the children of Israel to see the
promised man Moses was only allowed to
see the promised land but he was not
allowed to continue on just as John the
Baptist was allowed to see the promised
man but was not allowed to continue on
no no no no there was a transition of
power from Moses to Joshua at the Jordan
just as there was a transition of power
from John the Baptist to Jesus at the
Jordan
the Bible says John says that that
Joshua Joshua Yeshua Joshua after he
crosses the Jordan chooses 12 men here
that they take these boulders and put he
chose 12 men just as Jesus chooses 12
men after he crosses the Jordan you
remember that Joshua after he crossed
the Jordan he goes into battle three
times once against Jericho twice against
AI three times after he crosses the
Jordan three three one two three
three times just as Jesus crosses the
Jordan and three times the enemy comes
at him to try to get the victory over
him and three times the enemy fails now
beloved it was after Joshua did this
that he takes the twelve and puts them
upon these mountains and if you go to
the New Testament and you look at
Matthew 4 Matthew 3 where Jesus is
baptized Matthew 4 where he goes into
the wilderness and it's 10 to 3 times in
the very next chapter in Matthew 5 and
verse 1 the Bible says in Jesus and
Jesus and Yeshua went up into a mountain
and when his disciples were set he began
to speak to them blessings 9 blessings
in all guys come on come on so beloved
okay we get these blessings but what
about this mountain of curses what about
that mountain what one of that mountain
have to deal with what why the mount of
curses well beloved it's very simple you
see on that mountain God had told Joshua
I want you to build an altar upon this
mountain and I want you to make a
sacrifice and I want my people to
rejoice on this mountain hold on a
second wait a minute rejoice on the
mountain in which you just spoke all
these curses God what are you talking
about why in the world would you ask us
to rejoice after hearing all these
curses and God says because on this
mountain
I told Joshua to build an altar and make
a sacrifice you guys the curses that
were meant for you
the curses that had us all terrified
that God was after us
God was out to destroy us those curses
is what Jesus took upon himself that you
and I might live if you want to know
what was in the cup that made Jesus
tremble
look at those 53 verses of curses that
he took on your behalf and my behalf you
see beloved it's when we behold this
when we behold this when we learn to
look up when we learn to open the
scriptures and say Jesus show me what
you did for me
show me the depth of your sight
you realize we're gonna be studying the
cross throughout all eternity like that
just blows my mind like this stuff you
know what Nana is what is manna what is
it
the bread of heaven right the bread of
heaven and what is it alike like a wafer
right like small pieces of bread yeah
small small a coriander seed manna manna
I want you to imagine this guy's in
heaven there's a table and from that
table is falling manner you don't look
excited
probably because you don't get what I'm
saying because what I'm saying is this
what's falling from the tables of heaven
are crumbs this stuff that we're like
the angels up in heaven are like wait
till they get up here because all we're
getting is the little piece the stuff we
can handle
we're just anything deep you've ever
heard in your life
just think crumbs any life changing like
what is the deepest thing of crumbs
it's pieces from the huge piece in
heaven
we're gonna be studying this thing
throughout all eternity and beloved
there is no greater thing that can set
our hearts on fire that can set the
church on fire but the reason we are
cold to each other
the reason that we don't know how to
forgive the reason that we don't know
how to share our faith the reason that
we're not doing these things beloved is
because I don't believe that we are
really looking up I believe we're
looking down we're looking at the wounds
we're looking at what other people are
doing where we're measuring ourselves
we're doing all this stuff and that's
the one thing we are not doing is
looking to Calvary and when those people
were being bitten by those serpents the
reason that they did not look up is
because they were obviously trying to
protect themselves by looking down if
I'm careful I just won't be bitten so
look down it would have been an exercise
of faith to look up but they chose they
had they wanted to look down to try to
save themselves
that's oh so many of us are doing
beloved listen to me the Bible was given
to us to focus our eyes on Jesus bottom
line every story in the Bible every
action in the Bible was given that we
might see Jesus in my remaining time
I can't I'm just gonna have to read this
to you because I have not yet memorized
it but the entire Bible is about Jesus
and once we learn to see the Bible with
new eyes it changes it's a game-changer
it's a game-changer listen guys the old
tape listen there are four offices in
the Old Testament how many everyone four
and those four offices who knows what
they are preach this one prophet what
else
Kings what else judges so they're kings
in the Old Testament
they're prophets their judges and their
priests do you know what the order of
those are what's first revealed in the
Bible what's the first major office in
the Bible its profits that's the book of
Genesis Noah Joseph Abraham prophets
what comes after the after the prophets
prease the book of Exodus yeah
the introduction of the priesthood
Leviticus numbers are that those are
that's where the priest comes into focus
who comes into focus next the judges you
have the book of Judges yet Samson
Jephthah the judges and in the last
office Kings prophet priest judge King
prophet priest judge King beloved the
very order of the entire Old Testament
is based upon Jesus who came here as a
prophet died was buried resurrected
ascended to heaven to become our high
priest in 1844 moved into judgments and
will return as king of kings and Lord of
lords
beloved let me tell you something I am
learning over the last few years that if
you want a witness to your non-adventist
friends who happen to be Christians talk
about Jesus so them Christ in the
scripture and I promise you
it will blow their minds and that'll be
like what else do you have to say wait
how did you see this
wait I'm telling you if we would only
learn to focus our mind and our eyes on
Jesus it will change everything for us
it will transform us because by
beholding we become changed so I'm going
to close with a composite sketch of
Jesus one day I'll memorize this and
I'll just do it from my head but until
that day I need you to listen
like Adam he was the son of God like
Samuel he was only a boy when he
discovers his mission in the temple like
Joseph he was thirty years old when he
came into prominence like Joshua he
crossed the Jordan to lead 12 like
Elijah he provided drink for the thirsty
like Moses he entered the wilderness to
wander for for forty days like Daniel he
overcame the temptation of appetite like
job he refused the sin of presumption
like like meshach Shadrach and Abednego
he refused to bow down before another
dawn like the man of God He healed a
weather hand like Elijah he raised the
dead and multiplied the bread and held
health lepers like Ezekiel he preached
to a stubborn and rebellious people and
spoke against the abominations being
done in the temple like Josiah he
exposed false worship like Enoch he
walked with God like Moses he knew that
his hour had come he gathered the twelve
to repeat the covenant and sang a song
before going out to die alone like David
he crossed the brook kidron as his
enemies pursued him like David he was
betrayed by his close friend who
eventually hung himself like Joel he
enters into a time of trouble in the
Garden of Gethsemane like job he was
tempted to think that God had forsaken
him like Joseph he was sold for silver
and deserted by his brothers like Joseph
with the butler and the Baker he was
placed between two men one forgiving the
other rejected like Samson he was beaten
bound and marked placed between two
pillars bowed his head and pushed and
when he died there was a great rumbling
and he saved more in his death and when
he was alive like Isaac he was given up
for sacrifice like Noah he was littered
up above the earth on wood so that all
men would be drawn to him like Nehemiah
he would cut he would not come down for
he had a great work to do
like Joel he prayed for his enemies like
Samson his death caused a great rumbling
in the earth like Elijah's dead bones
his death brought to life many who slept
in the grave like Jonah he was in the
belly of the earth three days and three
nights like David he delivered a deadly
blow to the head of his enemy like Moses
he was willing to be blotted out of the
book but was resurrected from the dead
like Samuel he
called out of his sleep to serve as
priests in the house of God like Jonah
he stayed for 40 days like Nehemiah he
finished the work like Elijah he was
raised into the heavens like Joseph he
was sent ahead to prepare a place for
his brothers like Daniel he interceded
on behalf of his people like Jacob while
he is away he is working for his bride
like Joseph he will investigate his
brethren before allowing them to enter
into the place he has prepared for them
like Moses he will descend from the
Mount upon an unexpected people like
Moses he will part the sky as Moses part
of the sea he will part the sky and lead
his people out of bondage of the grave
like Joshua he will lead his people into
the promised land
like David he will take his place as
rightful king like Solomon he will reign
in peace but for a thousand years like
Solomon he will answer all of our hard
questions like Gideon he will put down
the enemies of God at the end of the
millennium like Jaffa he will destroy
those who cannot speak the heavenly
language like Abraham he will be the
father of a great multitude and like
Joseph he will be reunited with his
loved ones
[Applause]
you know Jesus is the center of all
scriptures he is the center of all
scriptures every prophet every person in
the Bible that God has used was to show
us a snapshot of the life of Jesus and
what you just heard is a composite
sketch every prophet playing a different
part reflecting a different part of the
life of Jesus and believing when we keep
our eyes on him we will be transformed
into a composite sketch of Jesus and
when his image is reproduced in us then
he will come to claim his own let us
look up let us look up let us remember
that we are here by the grace of God
literally
when you walk outside this auditorium
today take a look at the air around you
take a look at the ground take a look at
the trees and realize that you are
standing here that this planet exists
because of what did not happen at the
cross Heavenly Father thank you that
that struggle between justice and mercy
had the outcome that it did if it were
anyone of us we would have chosen
differently but it was you and that's
why we are here
forgive us Lord for taking the sacrifice
of the son of God so lightly and Lord
with this renewed lease on life may we
truly be about your mission set our
hearts on fire and remind us that where
there is no wood where there is no wood
the fire goes out thank you Jesus may
the cross of Calvary ever be the center
this we pray in Jesus name Amen and amen